Guide to the Norman Macleod Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Norman Macleod papers
1905-1985
YCAL MSS 718
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
33.82
(89 boxes)
The Papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers, family papers, photographs, scrapbooks, and printed material that document the life and work of poet Norman Macleod. Also included are records of Pembroke Magazine, dating from 1968 to 1977, when Macleod was editor. The correspondence in the collection documents Macleod's career as a poet and editor of poetry magazines, as well as his personal and family life. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts of many of Macleod's poems, and drafts of his autobiography, Generations of Anger, that was unpublished during his lifetime. Pembroke Magazine Records include contributor files (containing submissions and correspondence with authors) and production files for each of the issues edited by Norman Macleod. The remaining material in the collection includes photographs of Macleod, family members, and associates, personal and family papers (including the autobiography of Norman Macleod's mother Alice Wicklund Mills), scrapbooks, and sound recordings of Macleod reading his poetry. The Papers are of interest not only for their documentation of Norman Macleod's life and work, but also for their documentation of twentieth-century American poetry journals, 'little magazines,' and the culture of literary journals generally.
Macleod, Norman, 1906-1985
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Norman Macleod, 1968-1985.
Separated Materials
Material acquired from sources other than Norman Macleod is described separately as the Norman Macleod Collection (YCAL MSS 751).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Audiocassettes in Box 74: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 75 (Reel-to-reel audiotape): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 76 (Record Album Storage): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 89 (Restricted Papers): Restricted until 2023. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
Norman Wicklund Macleod (1906-1985)
Norman Wicklund Macleod, poet, author, professor, and editor of Pembroke Magazine, was born in Salem, Oregon in 1906. He graduated from the University of New Mexico wtih a B.A. in 1930, with further studies at the University of Southern California, the University of Oklahoma, and Teachers College of Columbia University, where he received an M.A. in 1936. He began a lifelong career as a poet and editor in the 1920s, contributing to several "little magazines" and later becoming editor of Briarcliff Quarterly, and founding editor of Pembroke Magazine. Among his book-length publications are Horizons of Death (Parnassus, 1934), Pure as Nowhere (Golden Goose, 1952) and Selected Poems (1975). Macleod taught English and creative writing at several colleges and universities in the United States, as well as the University of Baghdad, Iraq, before becoming Professor of English at Pembroke State University in Pembroke, North Carolina. Macleod died in 1985 in Greeneville, North Carolina.
Biographical information from May, Hal (ed.) Contemporary Authors. Volume 116. Detroit: Gale Research Company, 1986. p. 297.
Scope and Contents
The Papers consist of correspondence, writings, personal papers, family papers, photographs, scrapbooks, and printed material that document the life and work of poet Norman Macleod. Also included are records of Pembroke Magazine, dating from 1968 to 1977, when Macleod was editor. The correspondence in the collection documents Macleod's career as a poet and editor of poetry magazines, as well as his personal and family life. Writings include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts of many of Macleod's poems, and drafts of his autobiography, Generations of Anger, that was unpublished during his lifetime. Pembroke Magazine Records include contributor files (containing submissions and correspondence with authors) and production files for each of the issues edited by Norman Macleod. The remaining material in the collection includes photographs of Macleod, family members, and associates, personal and family papers (including the autobiography of Norman Macleod's mother Alice Wicklund Mills), scrapbooks, and sound recordings of Macleod reading his poetry. The Papers are of interest not only for their documentation of Norman Macleod's life and work, but also for their documentation of twentieth-century American poetry journals, 'little magazines,' and the culture of literary journals generally.
Arrangement
Organized into ten series: I. Correspondence, 1911-1985. II. Writings, 1923-1984. III. Pembroke Magazine Records, 1968-1981. IV. Personal Papers, 1905-1984. V. Family Papers, 1905-1981. VI. Teaching Records, 1969-1976. VII. Photographs, 1905-1980. VIII. Sound Recordings, 1937-1984. IX. Printed Material, 1913-1984. X. Scrapbooks, 1935-1953.
Pembroke magazine; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Literature publishing -- United States; Little magazines -- United States; Periodical editors -- United States; Audiotapes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographic prints -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Sound recordings -- United States -- 20th Century; Videotapes -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Periodical editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Macleod, Norman, 1906-1985; MIlls, Alice Wicklund
- Correspondence, 1911-1985; Series I; 17.51; (42 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is both personal and professional, relating to Norman Macleod's writings, academic life, personal life, and Pembroke Magazine. Unless otherwise indicated, files include only incoming correspondence.
  - "A" General, 1965-1976; 2 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Ackley, Randall William and Mrs.
    - Incoming, 1969-1977; 3 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
    - Outgoing, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ahsahata Press, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Akeson, Leona, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Aldrich, Myrl
    - Incoming, 1969-1972; 2 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Incoming, 1972-1982; 6 (Box 2, Folder 11-16)
    - Incoming, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Outgoing, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - American Biographical Institute, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Applewhite, James, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Ault, J. B., 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "B" General, 1936-1975; 3 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
  - Baggett, Jack, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Baker, Donald W., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Ball, Richard and Jean, 1975-1985; 2 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
  - Barbee, Roger, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Barnes, Walter, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Barr, Maurice, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Barrax, Gerald W., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Barrington, Jay, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Bayes, Ronald H., incoming and outgoing, 1971-1985 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, incoming and outgoing, 1976-1978; 2 (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Gallup, Donald; Nesheim, Kenneth; Schoonover, David; and Yale University Library
  - Berthold, Dennis A., 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Bizzell, Grace, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Boyle, Kay, incoming and outgoing, 1936-1983 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Brand, Miller, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1975 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Brown, Michael, incoming and outgoing, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Butler, Harriet Holmes, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Butte, Francisca Sterling, incoming and outgoing, 1963-1975 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Butterick, George, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Butters, Avery, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Byrd, Frances and Marilyn, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - "C" General, 1940-1983; 2 (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, 1936-1978 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Carnes, Otis G., incoming and outgoing, 1967-1984 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Carver, James, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Chang, Diana, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Clan Macleod Society, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Clark, Steve, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Cobra Press, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Cohoe, Greg, 1972, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - College of Petroleum and Minerals, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Columbia University. Teachers College, 1935, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Conley, Robert J., 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Conroy, Jack, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1974 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Crews, Judson, 1969-1985; 2 (Box 6, Folder 62-63)
  - Crown Publishers, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - "D" General, 1939-1984 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Daddio, Dadda, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Dagenet, Ken, incoming and outgoing, 1930-1981; 2 (Box 7, Folder 67-68)
  - Dalmas, Victor
    - Incoming, 1970-1977; 4 (Box 7, Folder 69-72)
    - Incoming, 1970-1985; 4 (Box 8, Folder 73-76)
    - Third Party, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Decker, James A., 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - DeGasperi, Mark, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Deutsch, Babette, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1979 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Deveny, Mary A., incoming and outgoing, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Dictionary of International Biography, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Dittmer, Hans Olfred, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Dunn, Ralph, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - "E" General, 1968-1975 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Edminsten, Rufus, 1977-1984 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Emerson, Richard Wertz, incoming and outgoing, 1950-1952 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Evans, Lonnie
    - Incoming, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Outgoing, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - "F" General, 1959-1975 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Fisher, Thomas Michael, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Foreste, Crystal Wicklund, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Foster, Ray, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - French, Warren, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - "G" General, 1934-1975; 2 (Box 9, Folder 95-96)
  - Gallup, Donald, 1978-1984 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Gambardella, James, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Gardner, Philip, incoming and outgoing, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Geng, Veronica, incoming and outgoing, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Gibson, Grace, 1972-1983 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Gifford, Norval and Mayme, 1920-1974 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Giles, Dolores, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Goode, Stephen H., incoming and outgoing, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Gotham Book Mart, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Goudy, Nancy, 1971-1974 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Graham, Cynthia, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Graham, W. S., 1972-1981 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Grant, Robert, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Graves, Dorset, incoming and outgoing, 1965-1980 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Greene, Carmen, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Gregor, Arthur, incoming and outgoing, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Gregory, Eric, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Griffin, John C.
    - Incoming, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Outgoing, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Grimes, James, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Gurkin, Kathy, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - "H" General, 1939-1983 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Harris, Cathy, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Harris, Ella Arden, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Harris, Jocelyn Macleod
    - Incoming, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 121)
    - Outgoing, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 122)
    - Third Party, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Harris, Maryanne, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Hendry, James Findlay, 1938, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Hepworth, James, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Heyen, William, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - Hoffman, Daniel, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 128)
  - Hogan, Michael, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 129)
  - Holmes, Harriet, 1971-1976 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - Homan, Lois and Lt. John Raymond, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - Horace Gregory Award Committee, incoming and outgoing, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - Hotvedt, Kris
    - Incoming, 1968-1973; 3 (Box 12, Folder 133-135)
    - Incoming, 1974-1984; 6 (Box 13, Folder 136-141)
    - Outgoing, 1969-1983; 2 (Box 14, Folder 142-143)
    - Third party, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Huberman, Edward, incoming and outgoing, 1967-1975 (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - Hunt, James B., 1980-1984 (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Hunt, William A.
    - Incoming, 1974-1983; 7 (Box 14, Folder 148-154)
    - Incoming, 1984-1985; 2 (Box 15, Folder 155-156)
    - Outoing, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Third party, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 158)
  - "I" General, 1973-1976 (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - Ignatow, David, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1977 (Box 15, Folder 160)
  - Ignatow, Rose Graubart
    - Incoming, 1969-1979; 3 (Box 15, Folder 161-163)
    - Outgoing, 1969-1972 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Imperial Casualty and Indemnity Company, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 165)
  - Inman, Will, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 166)
  - "J" General, 1965-1984 (Box 16, Folder 167)
  - Jackson, Blyden, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 168)
  - Jackson, Elizabeth, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - Johns, Judith, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Johns, Richard, incoming and outgoing, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Johnson, Kurt
    - Incoming, 1965-1977 (Box 16, Folder 172)
    - Outgoing, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - Jones, English, incoming and outgoing, 1967-1975 (Box 16, Folder 174)
  - "K" General, 1934-1978 (Box 16, Folder 175)
  - Kaebitzsch, Reinhold Johannes, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 176)
  - Kalar, Joseph A. and Mrs., incoming, outgoing, and third party, 1929-1972 (Box 16, Folder 177)
  - Kennedy, Robert C., 1974-1977 (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Kimzey, Ardis, incoming and outgoing, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Kinney, Thomas L, outgoing, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Klein, Herbert, 1974-1980 (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - Koch, Vivienne, 1946-1949 (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - Krampf, Thomas, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Kraus-Thomson Organization, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1978 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - "L" General, 1939-1980; 2 (Box 17, Folder 185-186)
  - Lane, Pinkie Gordon, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Langer, Elinor, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Lefevere, Andre, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - Lewis, Lois, 1975-1984; 2 (Box 18, Folder 190-191)
  - Library of Congress, 1967-1976 (Box 18, Folder 192)
  - Lindsay, Maurice, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 193)
  - Locklear, Linda, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 194)
  - "M" General, 1931-1975; 3 (Box 18, Folder 195-197)
  - "M" General, 1976-1983 (Box 19, Folder 198)
  - MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1938-1970 (Box 19, Folder 199)
  - MacDonald, Ina and Hazel, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 200)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1971-1980 (Box 19, Folder 201)
  - Macleod, Anne Clarke, incoming and outgoing, 1963-1966 (Box 19, Folder 202)
  - Macleod, Barbara, 1977-1981 (Box 19, Folder 203)
  - Macleod, Catherine (copies), 1933-1934 (Box 19, Folder 204)
    Includes copies of third party correspondence.
  - Macleod, John, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 205)
  - Macleod, Murdo, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 206)
  - Macleod, Norman Griffith
    - Incoming, 1963-1973; 2 (Box 19, Folder 207-208)
    - Incoming, 1974-1984; 2 (Box 20, Folder 209-210)
    - Outgoing, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 211)
    - Third Party, 1969-1971 (Box 20, Folder 212)
  - Macleod, Norman William, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 213)
  - Macleod, Norman Z., 1939 (Box 20, Folder 214)
  - Macleod, Norval G., outgoing, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 215)
  - Macleod, Skye Wicklund
    - Incoming, 1969-1984; 3 (Box 20, Folder 216-218)
    - Outgoing, 1964-1977 (Box 21, Folder 219)
    - Third Party, 1967-1979 (Box 21, Folder 220)
  - Mangione, Jerre, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1973 (Box 21, Folder 221)
  - Marissael, Grace, 1974-1977 (Box 21, Folder 222)
  - Marsh, Richard, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 223)
  - Massimino, Myrl, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 224)
  - Mayhall, Jane, 1969-1975 (Box 21, Folder 225)
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1941-1950 (Box 21, Folder 226)
  - McDonald, Ken, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 227)
  - McKenzie, Donald, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 228)
  - McWilliams, Carey, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 229)
  - Mead, William, 1945-1984 (Box 21, Folder 230)
  - Meredith, William, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 231)
  - Merriam, H. G., 1936, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 232)
  - Miles, Steven, 1970-1984 (Box 21, Folder 233)
  - Miller, Heather, 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 234)
  - Miller, Howard, outgoing, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 235)
  - Mills, Alice Wicklund Macleod
    - Incoming, 1910-1975; 5 (Box 22, Folder 236-240)
    - Outgoing, 1915-1975; 3 (Box 23, Folder 241-243)
    - Third Party, 1910-1975; 2 (Box 23, Folder 244-245)
  - Mills, Patricia, 1970-1974 (Box 23, Folder 246)
  - Mills, Robert Parke, incoming and outgoing
    - Incoming, 1968-1985; 3 (Box 23, Folder 247-249)
    - Outgoing, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 250)
  - Millspaugh, Margaret, 1976-1984 (Box 24, Folder 251)
  - "N" General, 1969-1981 (Box 24, Folder 252)
  - Nabokov, Nikolai, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 253)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 254)
  - Nesheim, Kenneth
    See also: Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
    - Incoming, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 255)
    - Outgoing, 1968-1975; 2 (Box 24, Folder 256-257)
    - Third Party, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 258)
  - New Directions Publishing Corporation, 1974-1977 (Box 24, Folder 259)
  - The New Yorker, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 260)
  - North Carolina Arts Council, 1971-1976 (Box 25, Folder 261)
  - North Carolina Committee for Continuing Education in the Humanities, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 262)
  - North Carolina Writers Conference, 1973-1979 (Box 25, Folder 263)
  - "O" General, 1969-1985 (Box 25, Folder 264)
  - O'Katz, Tracy, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 265)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 266)
  - Ortiz, Simon, incoming and outgoing, 1973-1977 (Box 25, Folder 267)
  - Owen, Guy
    - Incoming, 1969-1975 (Box 25, Folder 268)
    - Outgoing, 1969-1974 (Box 25, Folder 269)
  - "P" General, 1936-1983; 2 (Box 25, Folder 270-271)
  - Patchen, Kenneth, 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 272)
  - Pauker, John, 1941-1975 (Box 26, Folder 273)
    Includes copies of third party correspondence
  - Pauli, Ken, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1981 (Box 26, Folder 274)
  - Pearce. T. M.
    - Incoming, 1935-1985; 3 (Box 26, Folder 275-277)
    - Outgoing, 1947-1951 (Box 26, Folder 278)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes
    - Incoming, 1968-1969; 2 (Box 26, Folder 279-280)
    - Incoming, 1969-1974; 6 (Box 27, Folder 281-286)
    - Incoming, 1975-1977 (Box 28, Folder 287)
    - Outgoing, 1968-1970; 5 (Box 28, Folder 288-292)
    - Outgoing, 1971-1973; 5 (Box 29, Folder 293-297)
    - Outgoing, 1973-1974; 4 (Box 30, Folder 298-301)
    - Outgoing, 1974-1981; 3 (Box 31, Folder 302-304)
    - Third Party, 1969-1974; 2 (Box 31, Folder 305-306)
  - Peck, Ruth
    - Incoming, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 307)
    - Incoming, 1977-1985 (Box 32, Folder 308)
    - Outgoing, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 309)
  - Peden, William
    - Incoming, 1947-1985; 2 (Box 32, Folder 310-311)
    - Outgoing, 1946-1969 (Box 32, Folder 312)
    - Third Party, 1947-1970 (Box 32, Folder 313)
  - Pembroke State University, 1977-1983 (Box 32, Folder 314)
  - The Pilot, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 315)
  - Pisano, Richard C., incoming, outgoing, and third party, 1969-1984 (Box 32, Folder 316)
  - Platt, Eugene, 1972-1975 (Box 33, Folder 317)
  - Pollack, Felix, 1970-1984 (Box 33, Folder 318)
  - Pound, Dorothy, undated (Box 33, Folder 319)
  - Prins, Ina, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 320)
  - Prins, Sonya, incoming and outgoing, 1964-1975 (Box 33, Folder 321)
  - Putnam, Riva, incoming and outgoing, 1967-1973 (Box 33, Folder 322)
  - Putnam, Samuel, 1935-1946 (Box 33, Folder 323)
  - "R" General, 1928-1980; 2 (Box 33, Folder 324-325)
  - Ragan, Sam, incoming and outgoing, 1971-1975 (Box 33, Folder 326)
  - Raisig, L. Miles, 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 327)
  - Rakosi, Carl, 1971-1975 (Box 33, Folder 328)
  - Ray, Shreela, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 329)
  - Republic of Iraq Embassy, 1962-1963 (Box 33, Folder 330)
  - Reuben, William, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 331)
  - Richmond Technical Institute, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 332)
  - Robert College of Istanbul, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 333)
  - Rochdale College, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 334)
  - Root, Frances Bowen Macleod, 1975-1985; 2 (Box 34, Folder 335-336)
  - Rose, Charles G., 1973-1975 (Box 34, Folder 337)
  - Rosenblum, Martin, incoming and outgoing, 1971-1976 (Box 34, Folder 338)
  - Rosenthal, M. L., 1972-1974 (Box 34, Folder 339)
  - Roulston, Rosiland, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 340)
  - Royle, Trevor, 1975-1977 (Box 34, Folder 341)
  - Rundus, Raymond J., 1971-1978 (Box 34, Folder 342)
  - "S" General, 1943-1983 (Box 34, Folder 343)
  - "S" General, 1938-1985; 4 (Box 35, Folder 344-347)
  - Salzman, Jack, incoming and outgoing, 1970-1974 (Box 35, Folder 348)
  - Scheele, Karl A., 1976-1984 (Box 35, Folder 349)
  - Schoonover, David, incoming and outgoing, 1980-1984 (Box 35, Folder 350)
  - Sharp, Tom, incoming and outgoing, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 351)
  - Sherby, Jack M.
    - Incoming, 1969-1985; 4 (Box 36, Folder 352-355)
    - Outgoing, 1969-1980 (Box 36, Folder 356)
  - Sigma Chi Fraternity, 1942-1976 (Box 37, Folder 357)
  - Simpson, Alva, 1973-1974 (Box 37, Folder 358)
  - Smith, Sydney Goodsir, 1974-1977 (Box 37, Folder 359)
  - Smoller, Sanford J.
    - Incoming, 1974-1985; 4 (Box 37, Folder 360-363)
    - Outgoing, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 364)
  - Spady, James, 1976-1977 (Box 38, Folder 365)
  - Spiré, Andre, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 366)
  - Spivey, Kregg, 1975-1977 (Box 38, Folder 367)
  - Stem, Thad, incoming and outgoing, 1971-1976 (Box 38, Folder 368)
  - Stephenson, Shelby, 1977-1985; 2 (Box 38, Folder 369-370)
  - Sterling, Cary, 1968-1977 (Box 38, Folder 371)
  - Strick, Hilda, 1974-1983 (Box 38, Folder 372)
    Includes third party correspondence.
  - "T" General, 1969-1975 (Box 39, Folder 373)
  - Tallman, Ray, 1974-1983 (Box 39, Folder 374)
  - Tate, Allen, 1943-1968 (Box 39, Folder 375)
  - Thirlwall, John C., incoming and outgoing, 1968-1971 (Box 39, Folder 376)
  - Thomson, Eugene, 1971-1974 (Box 39, Folder 377)
  - Tolbert, Mildred, 1982, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 378)
  - Trego, Charlotte, 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 379)
  - Trieber, Marshall, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1970 (Box 39, Folder 380)
  - Trusky, Thomas, 1975-1984; 3 (Box 39, Folder 381-383)
  - Tunstall, Catherine Herbert Stuart Macleod
    - Incoming, 1931-1981; 2 (Box 40, Folder 384-385)
    - Outgoing, 1930-1932 (Box 40, Folder 386)
  - "U" General, 1928-1980 (Box 40, Folder 387)
  - University Microfilms, incoming and outgoing, 1969-1984 (Box 40, Folder 388)
  - University Nursing Center at Greenville, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 389)
  - University of Missouri at Columbia, 1977-1978 (Box 40, Folder 390)
  - University of Queensland, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 391)
  - "V" General, 1969-1976 (Box 40, Folder 392)
  - "W" General, 1937-1983 (Box 41, Folder 393)
  - Wadley, Don, 1964-1972 (Box 41, Folder 394)
  - Wald, Alan, incoming and outgoing, 1976-1979 (Box 41, Folder 395)
  - Walker, Mae, 1968-1977 (Box 41, Folder 396)
  - Warfel, Harry, incoming and outgoing, 1944-1969 (Box 41, Folder 397)
  - Warren, Gene, 1978, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 398)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, third party, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 399)
  - Weber, Brom, 1972-1975 (Box 41, Folder 400)